This is the first of the series of videos on programming language semantics and in
这是关于编程语言语义的系列视频的第一部分，在
particular on the semantics of cool, Before we dive into technical details
在我们深入到技术细节之前，请先详细了解Cool的语义
though I want to spend a few minutes talking about what programming language
虽然我想花几分钟谈谈什么编程语言
semantics are and why we need them. The problem we have to address is that we need
语义学是我们需要它们的原因。我们必须解决的问题是我们需要
some way to say what behavior we expect when we run a Kuhl program. So, for every
某种方式可以说，当我们运行Kuhl程序时，我们期望什么行为。所以，对于每一个
kind of Kuhl expression, for everyone we have to say what happens when it's
一种库尔式的表达，对于每个人，我们必须说当它发生时会发生什么
evaluated and we can regard this as the meaning of the expression. Somehow, give
我们可以把这看作是表达式的意思。不管怎样，给出
rules to specify what a particular, what kind of computation of a particular
规则来指定特定的是什么、特定的是什么类型的计算
expression does. And I think it's useful to look back and see how we dealt with
表达式可以。我认为回顾过去，看看我们是如何处理
this with similar problems in defining other parts of cool, okay the earlier
这在定义酷的其他部分时也有类似的问题，好的，前面的
things that we looked at in this course. So for example For Lexical Analysis we
我们在这门课上看到的东西。例如，对于词法分析，我们
defined a family of family of tokens using regular expressions And for the, the
使用正则表达式定义了一系列令牌族，对于
syntax of the language we used Context Free Grammars to specify the, the
语言的语法我们使用上下文无关文法来指定，
structure of the, how words could be strong together to form valid sentences in
的结构，单词如何结合在一起才能形成有效的句子
Kuhl And then for the semantic analysis we gave formal typing rules And now we're to
Kuhl，然后为了语义分析，我们给出了形式化的类型规则，现在我们要
the point that we have to talk about how the programs actually running so we have
这一点是我们必须讨论程序是如何实际运行的，所以我们有
to give some evaluation rules and these are going to guide how we do code
给出一些评估规则，这些规则将指导我们如何编写代码
generation of optimization or you going to determine what the program should do and
生成优化，或者您要确定程序应该做什么，以及
what kind of transformations we can do on programs to make them run faster or use a
我们可以对程序执行哪些类型的转换以使它们运行得更快，或者使用
space or what other, what any other kind of optimization that we would like to
空间或其他什么，我们想要什么其他类型的优化
perform. So far we've been specifying the evaluation rules somewhat indirectly.
表演。到目前为止，我们在某种程度上间接地指定了评估规则。
We've been doing it by giving a complete compilation strategy down to stack machine
我们一直在通过向堆栈机器提供完整的编译策略来做到这一点
code and then we've been talking about the evaluation rules for the stack machine or
代码，然后我们一直在讨论堆叠机的求值规则，或者
actually translation the stack machine into assembly code And that is certainly a
实际上将堆栈机器翻译成汇编代码，这肯定是一个
complete description. You can take the generated assembly code and get it right
完整的描述。您可以获取生成的汇编代码并使其正确
out of the machine, and see what the program do es and that would be a, a
走出机器，看看程序做了什么，那将是一个，一个
legitimate description of the behavior of the program And the question then is, you
程序行为的合法描述，那么问题是，您
know, why isn't that good enough. Why isn't just having a code generator for the
知道吗，为什么这还不够好。为什么不只有一个代码生成器用于
language. Why is that already a good enough transcription of what how the code
语言。为什么已经足够好的抄写了什么代码呢
is supposed to be executed And The answer to that is maybe a little hard to
应该被处决，这个问题的答案可能有点难
appreciate without having a written a few compilers But in a nutshell, people have
无需编写几个编译器即可欣赏，但简而言之，人们已经
learned through hard experience that assembly language descriptions of language
从艰苦的经历中学到汇编语言对语言的描述
implementations, language implementations, have a lot of irrelevant detail. There's a
实现，语言实现，有很多不相关的细节。有一个
lot of things that you have to say when you get such a complete executable
当您获得如此完整的可执行文件时，您必须要说的事情有很多
description that was not necessary to say about how the program executes. So for
不需要说明程序如何执行的描述。所以对于
example the fact that we use a stack machine, that's not intrinsic to the
例如，我们使用堆栈机器，这不是
implementation of any particular programming language. There are other
任何特定编程语言的实现。还有其他的
co-generation strategies that we could have used so you know you don't have to do
我们本可以使用的热电联产策略，所以你知道你不必
the stack machine to implement the language which way the stack grows.
堆栈机器实现堆栈成长的语言。
Whether it grows towards high addresses or low addresses you could implement it
无论它朝向高地址还是低地址增长，您都可以实现它
either way. How it, it, yeah, exact representation of integers in a particular
不管是哪种方式。它，它，是的，如何精确地表示一个特定的整数
instructions actually used to execute or to implement certain language constructs.
实际用于执行或实现某些语言构造的指令。
All of these things are, are a, are one way or, or one particular way to implement
所有这些都是，是一种，是一种方式，或者是一种特定的方式来实现
the language but we don't want them to, to be taken as the only way that the language
语言，但我们不希望它们，被认为是语言的唯一途径
could be implemented. So, what we really want than it has a complete description
可以实施。所以，我们真正想要的比它有一个完整的描述
but one that is not overly restrictive One that will allow a variety of different
但是它不会有太多的限制，它将允许各种不同的
implementations. And when people have not done this when people have not tried to
实施。当人们没有做到这一点的时候，当人们还没有试着这样做的时候
find some relatively high level way of describing the behavior of languages,
找到一些相对较高层次的方式来描述语言的行为，
they've been inevitably gotten into the situation where they a, where people would
他们不可避免地陷入了这样的境地，在那里，人们会
just have to go and run the program on a reference implementation or to decide what
只需在参考实现上运行该程序，或者决定
it does. And so this is not a very satisfying a situation because of the
确实如此。所以这不是一个非常令人满意的情况，因为
reference implementation is not completely correct itself. It will have bugs and
引用实现本身并不完全正确。它会有窃听器和
there will be artifacts of the particular way it was implemented that you didn't
将会有您没有实现的特定方式的工件
mean to be part of a language but because there was no better definition wind up
意思是成为一种语言的一部分，但因为没有更好的定义
becoming fixed and have sort of accidents of the way the language was implemented
变得固定，并且在实现语言的方式上有某种偶然性
the first time. So there are many ways to actually specify semantics that would be
第一次。因此，有许多方法可以实际指定语义，即
suitable for our task and it turns out that these are all equally powerful but
适合我们的任务，事实证明，它们都同样强大，但是
some of them are more suited to various tasks than others so the one that we're
他们中的一些人比另一些人更适合各种任务，所以我们现在
going to be using is called operational semantics. So operational semantics
将要使用的被称为操作语义学。所以操作语义学
describes program evaluation via execution roles on an abstract machine we just gave
描述通过我们刚才给出的抽象机器上的执行角色进行的程序评估
a bunch of rules that say you know from particular expression how it should be
一堆规则，说你从特定的表达中知道它应该是什么样子
executed. You can think of this as a very, very high level kind of co-generation And
被处决了。你可以认为这是一种非常、非常高水平的热电联产
this is most useful for specifying implementations and it is what we're going
这对于指定实现是最有用的，这也是我们要做的
to use to describe the semantics of Kuhl. I want to mention two other ways of. Of
用来描述库尔的语义。我想提一下另外两种方法。的
specifying programming language semantics because they're, they're important and you
指定编程语言语义，因为它们非常重要，而您
may come across them at some point outside of this class. One is the notational
可能会在这堂课之外的某个时间遇到他们。一种是记号式的
semantics and here the programs meaning is actually given as a mathematical function.
语义学，这里的程序含义实际上是以数学函数的形式给出的。
So the program text is mapped to a function that goes from input and outputs
因此，程序文本被映射到从输入到输出的函数
and this, this is, this function is an actual function that exist in the
而这个，就是这个函数是一个实际的函数，它存在于
mathematical sense And this is a very elegant approach but it uses complexities
数学感，这是一种非常优雅的方法，但它使用了复杂性
into finding an appropriate class of functions and we don't really need to
找到合适的函数类，我们真的不需要
consider for the purposes of just describing an implementation. And another
仅出于描述实现的目的而考虑。和另一个
important approach is axiom semantics and here program behaviors described in some
重要的方法是公理语义，这里的程序行为描述在一些
kind of logic And the basic kinds of statements that you write in this language
一种逻辑和你用这种语言写的基本语句
or in this, in this in the axiomatic semantics is that if execution begins in a
或者在这种情况下，在公理语义中的这种情况下，如果执行开始于
state satisfying x, then it ends in the state satisfying y where x and y are
满足x的状态，则它以满足y的状态结束，其中x和y是
formulas in some logic And this is a very common foundation for syst ems that
一些逻辑中的公式，这是系统EMS的一个非常常见的基础，
analyze programs automatically that tries to prove facts about programs either to
自动分析程序，该程序尝试证明有关程序的事实
prove they're correct or to discover bugs in programs.
证明它们是正确的，或者发现程序中的错误。